Let's take our example of the VGG network.
我们以 VGG 网络为例
You may be wondering how can I take the CNN that's been trained to
我们现在要解决的问题是
classify a thousand ImageNet images and apply this to a new problem.
如何将这个能分类 1000 种 ImageNet 图像的已训练 CNN 应用到新的任务上
What if I wanted to classify images of different flower types?
如果我想分类不同类型的花朵呢？
Like sunflowers versus daisies,
例如太阳花与雏菊
roses, and so on.
玫瑰等
While VGG has learned to distinguish between
虽然 VGG 学会区分
the thousand different categories that are present in ImageNet,
ImageNet 中的一千种不同类别
most of those categories are animals,
但是大多数类别是动物
fruits and vegetables, or everyday objects.
水果 蔬菜或日常物品
Is VGG trained each of its convolutional layers learn to extract
VGG 是否训练每个卷积层学习提取
some information about the shapes and colors that distinguish these different objects?
关于区分这些不同对象的形状和颜色信息？
In fact, we know that the convolutional filters in
实际上 我们知道已训练 CNN 中的卷积滤波器
a trained CNN are arranged in a kind of hierarchy.
按照某种层级排列
The filters in the first layer often detect edges or blocks of color.
第一层级中的滤波器通常会检测边缘或色块
The second layer might detect circles, stripes, and rectangles.
第二层可能会检测圆圈 条纹和长方形
These are still very general features that are
这些依然是很通用的特征
useful in analyzing any image in almost any dataset.
有助于分析几乎任何数据集中的任何图像
The filters in the final convolutional layers are much more specific.
最终卷积层中的滤波器更加具体
If they were birds in the training dataset,
如果训练数据集中有小鸟
there are filters that can detect birds.
那么就有检测小鸟的滤波器
If they were cars or bicycles,
如果有汽车或自行车
there are filters to detect wheels and so on.
那么就有检测轮子的滤波器 等等
We'll see then that it's useful to remove the final layers of the network that
我们发现 删除特定于训练数据集的最后层级
are very specific to the training dataset while keeping the earlier layers.
并保留前面的层级很有用
In this way, you can use the convolutional
这样的话 你可以使用
and pooling layers in a pre-trained network like
VGG 等预训练网络中的卷积层和池化层
VGG is a feature extractor that identifies
作为特征提取器
shape and color-based features in your set of flower images.
它们能够识别花朵图像数据集中的形状和颜色特征
Then, after an image has passed through this pre-trained feature extractor,
然后 使图像经过这个预训练的特征提取器后
we can add one or two more linear layers at the end,
我们可以在最后添加一两个线性层级
which can act as a final classifier.
作为最终分类器
These last players take in the features from an image and we can train
最终层级会接受图像中的特征
only these final layers to customize this network for a new task.
我们只训练最终层级并针对新任务自定义此网络
So, even if the image database that you're interested in for
即使你要处理的花朵图像数据库
flower images has no overlap with the ImageNet categories,
与 ImageNet 类别没有重叠部分
it's still possible to use the knowledge from a pre-trained CNN.
我们依然能利用预训练 CNN 中的经验
This is one technique for transfer learning,
这就是一种迁移学习技巧
but your method will depend on both the size of your dataset
但是你的方法取决于你的数据集的大小
and the level of similarity it shares with the ImageNet database.
以及它与 ImageNet 数据库之间的相似性
For instance, this technique of adding
例如 如果你的数据集相对较小
some final trainable classifier layers will work well if
并且具有和在 ImageNet 数据库中发现的特征
your dataset is relatively small and has
相似的独特形状特征
distinct shape features that are similar to those found in the ImageNet database.
那么添加最终可训练分类器层级效果将不错
If your dataset is very large and different than ImageNet,
如果你的数据集很大 并且与 ImageNet 不一样
you may take a different approach.
你可以采用其他方法
Let's go over one more approach to transfer learning before we implement this in code.
我们再介绍一种迁移学习方法 然后再实现代码